connectedplanetonline.com 2014-10-20

# Privacy Policy - Penton

Penton (also referred to in this Privacy Policy with the terms “we,” “us,” or “our”) is committed to protecting the privacy of all those who provide us with their contact information while using our websites, products, events, or services (“you” or “Users”). This policy describes the ways that personally identifiable and anonymous information about our publication subscribers, online and digital media product users, and event registrants is collected, how that information might be shared, and how someone can request changes to the way their personal information is used or shared.  
A current list of the Penton websites covered by this Privacy Policy (the “Sites”) can be found here.

#### Information We Collect

We may collect personally identifiable and/or anonymous information from you in the course of your use of our websites, products, events, or services (“Services”) as further described in this Privacy Policy. Personally identifiable information is information that can identify you, such as your full name, email address, postal address, telephone number, and fax number. In some cases, you may provide information to us, and in others information about you or your activities on our Services may be automatically collected, as further described below.

#### Information You Provide

We collect personally identifiable information that you provide to us when you subscribe to our magazines (either directly or through another company such as a subscription agency); sign up for email newsletters or promotions; enter a contest; participate in surveys; register for a website, webcast, mobile application, tradeshow or other online or in-person event; or otherwise communicate with us or interact with the Sites. We also may receive information about you from other sources and add it to the information you have provided to us.

If you use a credit card to pay for a Penton product or service, we may retain your credit card information in order to renew your account in the event you elect to renew your subscription. When we do retain credit card information, we keep it secure and separate from other demographic information you may have given us.

Penton is not responsible for the information you volunteer about yourself in discussions in our forums or other publicly accessible interactions, or the information that you choose to make public in your member profile. To view or change your member profile, please return to the Penton business site where you registered.

#### Information Collected Automatically and Our Uses of Such Information

Like most website operators, we use cookies (small data files stored on your computer by your web browser upon visiting a website), web beacons, and similar technologies to operate our Services efficiently and as intended. Through such technologies we gather information about you, such as your browser type, operating system, IP address, mobile device identification number, the sites visited before and after our Site, and about your interactions with our Services, such as the time and date when you viewed a page, which advertisements you have clicked on, and whether you filled out an online form. You may set your browser to block all cookies, including Penton’s, while using our Services (in which case some aspects of the Services may not function properly), or you may set your browser to block third-party cookies and allow first-party cookies, which would allow us (but not third parties) to collect such information while you are on our Sites. In addition, some browsers may allow you to block certain web beacons and similar tracking codes. Please refer to your browser’s documentation if you wish to block some or all cookies, web beacons, and/or similar tools.

We use information gathered through these tools to improve the way our Sites work, for example by employing third-party analytics tools which aggregate anonymized user information to help us better design our Sites, and to enhance the functionality of our Services, for example by remembering preferences or other choices that you make, such as user names, language preferences, and the like. By allowing us to understand how you use our site over time, these tools can help us provide you with a better, more relevant online experience. In addition, we may work with third-party advertising companies to target and serve advertising you see on the Services or on third-party sites based on preferences gleaned from such information. For example, we work with a company called Bizo that may, based on your activities on our Sites and/or third party sites in Bizo’s network, serve ads for our or third-party products to you when you visit another site in Bizo’s network. You can review Bizo’s privacy policy at [http://www.bizo.com/privacy_policy](http://www.bizo.com/privacy-policy/), and can opt-out of Bizo-targeted advertising at <http://www.bizo.com/opt-out/>.

#### Third-Party Cookies and Tracking Technologies

Certain third parties may also employ cookies, web beacons, and/or similar technologies on our Services. Information collected through such third-party tools is gathered directly by such third party, not by Penton, and is subject to such third party’s applicable privacy policy. Penton has no control over such third-party tools. These third parties include but are not limited to analytics partners who help us better understand how our users are interacting with our Services and advertising, providers of widgets and other third-party applications that may appear in our Services, ad servers, ad networks, ad agencies, and advertisers. You may visit these third parties’ sites to learn more about their privacy practices. In addition, as noted above, you may set your browser to block third-party cookies. Finally, you may visit the industry websites described in the next section to learn more about the privacy practices of a wide range of ad networks and data companies and to exercise certain opt-out options made available there.

#### Industry Websites Regarding Online Behavioral Advertising

Most of the third-party advertising and data companies with whom we work (including Bizo) are members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) and/or the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”). NAI offers a tool which will allow you to opt-out of behavioral advertising by NAI members at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>, and the DAA offers a similar opt-out tool regarding behavioral advertising by its members at <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>. Finally, the DAA manages its Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising (“Self-Regulatory Program”); if you are served an ad by a third party that follows the Self-Regulatory Program, you may click on the Advertising Option Icon (the letter “i” in a blue triangle) or related phrases (e.g., “Why did I get this ad?,” “Interest Based Ads,” or “Ad Choices”) to learn more about applicable behavioral advertising practices and opt-out options.

#### How We Use Your Contact Information

We may use your contact information to send you account notices, including subscription renewals or registration confirmation, and to provide you with information about products or services you’ve ordered or which we think may be of interest to you. We may also use your contact information to ask for your input to help in our research about our services, events, or products or to provide you with additional information about the Sites.

We may also send you e-newsletters with targeted, relevant content. Each e-newsletter will provide you with an opportunity to unsubscribe from that particular e-newsletter. Unsubscribing from one newsletter will not affect delivery of other newsletters.

In some cases, we may send you relevant, carefully-screened offers from reputable third party businesses or organizations. Many of our customers appreciate receiving these offers because they relate to their business or occupation. However, you will always be able to opt-out of receiving future third party offers.

All promotional and research email messages you receive from us will include an option to opt-out of future email communications from that particular Penton brand.

#### Information We Share with Third Parties

We may provide personally identifiable information to those acting as our agents in providing our products and services, including third-party companies we have employed to provide us with specialized services, including customer service, subscription fulfillment, research, statistical analysis, list cleansing, postal mailings, email and fax deployment, telemarketing, and other information services. In compliance with privacy laws, we also provide our opt-out lists to those third-party companies so that they can be suppressed from the communications those companies send on Penton’s behalf.

From time to time our sponsors wish to contact our subscribers and customers who have indicated an interest in the products, services or events provided by such sponsors. If you register for products or services offered by such sponsors or third parties, or for events sponsored in whole or in part by a third party, or otherwise opt-in to permit us to share your personally identifiable information, then you may receive communications directly from such third parties. If you provide information on a co-branded site or while using a co-branded service, you grant us permission to share the information you have provided with that service or site partner. Their use of your information is subject to their privacy policies and we urge you to read those policies and be aware of their privacy practices before registering.

In addition, we may share your contact information with sponsors who appear in a particular e-newsletter of ours if you click on their link in the e-newsletter. If you do NOT wish to have your email address shared with that e-newsletter’s sponsors, you will be given an opportunity within the e-newsletter to opt-out.

Penton also shares the information it gathers in a compiled format with advertisers and other partners. The compiled format does not include personally identifiable information.

#### Content Quality Control

Penton uses a third party to monitor user-generated content posted on our websites. When you submit a comment on a Penton website, our third-party service provider, Mollom BVBA (“Mollom”), may collect, analyze, and store information about you and the content you submit for anti-spam and quality monitoring purposes as set forth in Mollom’s privacy policy available at <https://mollom.com/web-service-privacy-policy>.

#### Information Transfer

Penton is based in the United States of America. Any information you provide may be stored and maintained in a secure database in the United States or transferred to a secure database outside the United States. By providing us with your information, you consent to this transfer.

In the case of a change of ownership or a merger involving Penton or any business that is part of Penton, your contact information associated with that business would be one of those transferred assets. Users should also be aware that courts of equity, such as U.S. Bankruptcy Courts, might have the authority under certain circumstances to permit personal information to be shared or transferred to third parties without permission.

#### How We Keep Your Information Secure

We use reasonable precautions, including appropriate technical, administrative, and physical procedures, to protect personal information from loss, misuse, or alteration.

When we contract with other companies to provide us with services, we only share personal information with those that we believe share our commitment to privacy and information security. However, we are not responsible for any breach of security or for the actions of these parties.

Due to the design of the Internet and other factors outside our control, we cannot guarantee that communications between you and our servers will be free from unauthorized access by third parties.

#### Children’s Privacy

Penton’s Sites are not intended for use by children, especially those under the age of 13. No one under the age of 13 should provide any personal information or participate in any forums, chats, or online discussions. Minors under the age of 18 are prohibited from making purchases, including subscriptions, on our sites. Please discourage your children from providing any personal information about themselves to anyone in any public discussion areas.

#### California Privacy Rights

Under California Law, California residents have the right to request certain information from businesses with whom they have an established business relationship. In particular, the law provides that companies must inform consumers about the categories of personal information that have been shared with third parties, the names and addresses of those third parties, and examples of the types of services or products marketed by those third parties. To request the above information in relation to any of the Sites, please contact us via email addressed to [privacy@penton.com](mailto:privacy@penton.com) or write to us at: Penton, Attn: Customer Service – Privacy, 9800 Metcalf Avenue, Overland Park, KS 66212, with a reference to California Disclosure Information. We will respond to such requests to information access within 30 days following receipt at the e-mail or mailing address stated above. If we receive your request at a different e-mail or mailing address, we will respond within a reasonable period of time, but not to exceed 150 days from the date received. Please note that we are only required to respond to each customer once per calendar year.

#### Changes to this Privacy Policy

We may occasionally update this Privacy Policy. When we do, we will also revise the “last updated” date below. For changes to this Privacy Policy that may be materially less restrictive on our use or disclosure of your personal information, we will attempt to notify you by email of the change. We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy from time to time to stay informed about how we are protecting the personal information we collect. If you continue to use our site or services after we have attempted to contact you about material changes to the Privacy Policy, we will assume that you agree to the changes.

#### Terms of Use

By using any of our Sites, you consent to our use of your contact information as it is outlined in this Privacy Policy.

Penton reserves the right to access and disclose personally identifiable information to comply with applicable laws, lawful government requests and court orders, or to investigate alleged fraud or violations of the Terms of Use of Penton’s Sites.

All users, including those users who access the Sites from a country other than the U.S., agree that the laws of the State of New York shall govern any dispute, including those arising from Penton’s use of personal information or otherwise relating to privacy.

#### How to Reach Us

If you wish to update your print magazine subscription contact information, please go to the magazine’s home page. If you wish to opt-out of receiving email, faxes, or phone calls from any Penton business, please send an email to [privacy@penton.com](mailto:privacy@penton.com) or write/call us at:

**Penton Customer Service**  
9800 Metcalf Avenue  
Overland Park, KS 66212  
Phone: 913-967-1710

* * * * * *

This Agreement was last updated on May 6, 2013
